explain describe descendant wisdom what
is that knowing the nature of things
knowing things in their nature
that's what wisdom is so that doesn't
mean knowing about things or having all
the information about the things it's a
different thing collecting information
is or retaining information that's on
the level of intelligence and that can
help if you know where to look for the
nature of a present experience nature of
feelings nature of perception nature
suffering nature of things that matters
that's not necessarily determined by
intelligence but by wisdom and by effort
put in there wisdom you know born
nobody's born with wisdom people are
born with different intelligence but
wisdom is developed through effort
restraint calming of your mind giving in
to craving and desires all of these are
according the suitors the weak weakness
of wisdom because they all go against it
so that's that's basically what what
discernment is knowing the nature of
things
what is nature well the nature of things
different different things obviously are
different in the nature but most
universally they do all meeting that or
rather share the same nature which is
whatever I was talking about the nature
of all all determinations is the
impermanence the nature the nature of
all the terminations is suffering and in
the nature of all things its they cannot
be owned they cannot be yours they don't
belong to you they're there for you you
can use them but you're making a grave
error in maintaining your assumption of
ownership in regard to them that's the
root of all the problems as well it's
not the usage of things it's the the
ownership that you maintain
so that's the nature you want to be
concerned about as in you know you can
you can investigate other nature there's
a but that's all relative you wonder you
want to come to the root of the nature
of all things which is impermanence and
cannot be yours because that's really
all the matters that wisdom because
that's what wisdom is you're starting it
from wrong in that question you would
say how would you call knowing the
nature and I would answer I would call
it a wisdom so you can call it whatever
you want but you start why is that of
wisdom implying you already have the
idea of what wisdom is so why is that
that wisdom but it's it's other way
around you don't have to call it wisdom
call it any other other word but if
you'll be cold like that why because it
takes you it takes you it takes you
beyond things makes you make yeah it
literally takes you beyond things you're
not affected by them you cannot be
accessed by them why because you remove
your well you remove your ownership if
you things are not yours you won't be
emotionally affected by what happens to
them and that is wisdom that's elevation
of the mind which means a greater
perspective and things greater special
because all the decisions people make in
life intelligent people and non
intelligent people are based on the
degree the height so to speak of their
perspective and the height of the
perspective is were wisdom is people we
greater perspective maybe not the
ultimate perspective but we'll get it
they are wiser people they may not
necessarily be ultimately wise and know
the way out but they certainly wiser in
relation to those who just have no
perspective who are just like animals
following senses and sense desires so I
guess that's another way you can
describe wisdom it's the height of your
perspective universally speaking
surprised absolutely exactly exactly and
you can you cannot the greater the
wisdom is the less of an emotional
involvement with things you have which
means the ultimate wisdom is complete
surmounting of the feelings and
suffering does mean you are a robot you
just means you're a very wise person